# ATHARV MISHRA

# Android App Developer

+91-8755328239

atharvmishra77@gmail.com

My links:- <a href="https://atharv-portfolio-ashy.vercel.app">https://atharv-portfolio-ashy.vercel.app</a>

Noida

## **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Rising star in WIPRO Q4-2022
- Was part of NIT Rourkela Hacksagon 2023
- Among top Performers in 2023

#### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Technology

GL Bajaj Group Of Institutions,

Mathura

2017 - 2021

## **SKILLS**

- Languages: Kotlin, Java
- Development Tools: Android Studio
- Frameworks & Libraries: Android Jetpack, Retrofit, Room, Dagger Hilt, Coroutines
- Version Control: Git
- **UI/UX Design**:Material Design principles, responsive layouts
- **CI/CD Pipeline:** Jenkins.
- Architectures MVC & MVVM
- AI/ML NLP, ANN, Deep Learning

## **LANGUAGES**

- Hindi
- · English

# **OTHER PROJECTS**

#### Hello NITR App (NIT Rourkela)

- Built an app for **NIT Rourkela** that bridges the .communication gap between faculty and students.
- Made sure the app runs smoothly and handles data efficiently.

#### JCB App

- Also worked on a JCB app as a freelancer, focusing on design, backend, and user authentication.
- Used Java, Android Studio, and Firebase to build a seamless and user-friendly experience.

**Link:** <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?">https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?</a></a>
<a href="id=ayushgupta.nexa\_parts\_final">id=ayushgupta.nexa\_parts\_final</a>

## **ABOUT ME**

I'm a passionate Android developer with over 3 years of experience in creating mobile applications that enhance the user experience. My expertise lies in developing feature-rich Android apps using *Kotlin* and *Java*, with a strong focus on best practices and user-centric design.

My work: https://atharv-portfolio-ashy.vercel.app/

# WORK EXPERIENCE

# • Unnati AgriTech (Noida) Feb 2023- Present

## **Android App Developer**

**Ora Finance App** 

- Led end-to-end development of a robust loan application using MVVM architecture, integrating payment gateway, many APIs, E-Mandate, and KYC processes.
- Designed an elegant and intuitive UI, optimized app performance.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams, conducted code reviews, and mentored junior developers.
- Followed Best possible Coding Practices which resulted in almost no warnings in entire project.
- Implemented Firebase Crashlytics to stay updated about the App crashes on live

APP LINK: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.app.orafinancecustomer

#### U-store App (100K+ Downloads)

- Developed, tested and deployed multiple modules.
- · Integrated Payment Gateway and third party SDKs
- Migrated Entire Code-Base from Java to Kotlin .
- · Replaced async calls with Retrofit API.
- Replaced from SQLite to RoomDB for better data management and user experience.
- Improved overall app speed, functionality, and user satisfaction through thorough testing and optimization.

#### APP LINK: <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?">https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?</a>

id=com.unnatiagro.agripos&pcampaignid=web\_share

#### **OraFinance Field App**

- Led the entitre development of the OraFinance Field App for customer onboarding in loan services.
- Utilized MVVM architecture for a clean and maintainable codebase.
- Implemented Coroutines for efficient background processing.
- · Integrated REST APIs using Retrofit and managed dependencies with Dagger Hilt.
- Enhanced data management with Room Database.
- Streamlined the onboarding process for field agents, improving efficiency and customer interactions.

# • WIPRO Technologies (Gurugram) Aug 2021 - Feb 2023

#### **SDET (Software Development Engineer in Test)**

- Designed, developed, and maintained automated test scripts using Java Selenium framework.
- Worked on agile methodology with the help of tools like Jira and Confluenece.
- Integrated automated tests with the CI/CD pipeline to ensure continuous testing.
- Ensured that the automation coverage includes functional, regression, performance, and load testing.
- Worked closely with developers to understand the architecture and design of the software.
- Wrote and maintained code to support the development and automation of testing processes.

# LogicLadder Technologies (Gurugram) March 2021 - July 2021 Android App Developer (Intern)

- Contributed to developing an Android app for a sustainability management technology company.
- Worked on Bluetooth which collects the data from difference Sensors.
- Built user interfaces, integrated APIs.
- Worked under the guidance of senior developers to enhance app functionality.